<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  
  <!-- EN: starjack -->
  <Starjack.label>звездник</Starjack.label>
  <!-- EN: Engineered for life among the stars, starjack are built to withstand the unforgiving conditions of deep space living. Their reflective pressure-adaptive skin provides insulation against extreme temperatures and allows them to survive brief exposure to hard vacuum. These adaptations make them invaluable for spacewalk repairs and emergency decompression scenarios.\n\nMost starjack spend their lives beyond planetary gravity, leading to lower muscle mass and reduced physical strength compared to baseline humans. However, their resilience in zero-gravity environments makes them essential for maintaining orbital platforms and working aboard long-haul vessels.\n\nAs one of humanity’s oldest xenotypes, starjack played a crucial role in the colonization of space. They are a common sight on deep-space stations and interstellar ships, where genetic modification is often a more cost-effective solution than upgrading spacecraft to support unaltered human physiology. -->
  <Starjack.description>Разработанные для жизни среди звёзд, звездники созданы так, чтобы выдерживать суровые условия существования в открытом космосе. Их отражающая, адаптирующаяся к давлению кожа обеспечивает защиту от экстремальных температур и позволяет пережить кратковременное воздействие вакуума. Эти адаптации делают их незаменимыми при ремонте скафандров и в чрезвычайных ситуациях, связанных с разгерметизацией.\n\nБольшинство звездников проводят свою жизнь вне зоны притяжения планет, что приводит к снижению мышечной массы и физической силы по сравнению с обычными людьми. Однако их выносливость в невесомости делает их незаменимыми для обслуживания орбитальных платформ и работы на борту кораблей дальнего следования.\n\nБудучи одним из самых древних ксенотипов человечества, звездники сыграли важнейшую роль в колонизации космоса. Их часто можно встретить на станциях глубокого космоса и межзвёздных кораблях, где генетическая модификация часто оказывается более рентабельным решением, чем модернизация судов для поддержки неадаптированной человеческой физиологии.</Starjack.description>
  <!-- EN: Engineered for life among the stars, starjack are built to withstand the unforgiving conditions of deep space living. Their reflective pressure-adaptive skin provides insulation against extreme temperatures and allows them to survive brief exposure to hard vacuum. -->
  <Starjack.descriptionShort>Созданные для жизни среди звёзд, звездники способны выдерживать суровые условия открытого космоса. Их отражающая, адаптирующаяся к давлению кожа защищает от экстремальных температур и позволяет выживать при кратковременном воздействии вакуума.</Starjack.descriptionShort>
  
</LanguageData>